# Mihkel Lukats

# I FAD SOFTWARE ENGINEER

♥ Estonia, Tallinn☑ mihkel@progmatic.comin linkedin.com/in/mihkel-lukats/

### **Summary**

Lead software engineer with 7+ years of experience in building software and leading customer projects. I focus on creating software that increases business value. That requires close connection with customer and developing software in an agile way.

#### **Core Competencies**

- Team Leading
- Web Application Development
- Software Engineering
- Technical Leading
- Test Driven Development

- Mentoring
- Agile Software Development
- Java Development

# **Projects**

#### • PSD2 Payments

Built microservice to facilitate PSD2 payment flow in client information system.

### • Authentication Platform With Multilayered Cryptography

With small team designed, built and deployed successful Alpha on extremely tight schedule.

#### • Loan Platform

Built core day-change logic; improved loan scheduling; migrated system; launched project to live.

#### • Bank Saint Petersburg

Helped team to focus on their architectural goals and implementation of best practices.

### • Social Features for Payments

Implemented highly appreciated social features to payments. Which enabled users to express their emotions when making payments.

### • AB Testing And Conversion Analysis

Very successful co-operation with marketing team to increased e-commerce conversion through very quick deployments and customer behavior testing.

# **Work History**

# **Lead Software Engineer**

2018 - Present

Freelancer

Working as lead developer on client projects that need high quality and quick execution.

### Technologies used

- Java, Spring, JDBCTemplate, MyBatis, JPA, Hibernate
- JavaScript, HTML, CSS
- PostgreSQL
- ShellScript, Python
- Amazon Web Services
- Kafka, RabbitMQ

Software Craftsman 2017 - 2018

Codeborne

Promoted the use of best practices and practiced Extreme Programming.

### Technologies used

- Java, Play!, H2, JPA, Hibernate
- JavaScript, HTML, CSS
- PostgreSQL
- NodelS

Java Developer 2016 - 2017

Pocosys

### Technologies used

- Java, MyBatis
- PostgreSQL
- NodelS
- RabbitMQ

### Lead Java Developer

2014 - 2016

ON24 AS

As lead java developer worked very closely with marketing and iterated quickly to find best solutions to increase business value.

#### Technologies used

- Java, JDBC, Velocity
- Javascript, HTML, CSS
- PostgreSQL
- Basic, PHP, Shell Script

### Education

### **PyTorch Scholarship Challenge**

2018 - 2019

Udacity

Learned how to build models and algorithms using PyTorch

### **Deep Learning Nanodegree Foundation Program**

2017 - 2017

Udacity

This 4 month Nanodegree program students covered basic neural networks, convolutional neural networks, sequence to sequence models, and Generative adversarial neural networks. They also got familiarized with Google's TensorFlow framework.

Created with **TVisualCV**